Here I've read in an image of a monarch butterfly.
我已经读取了一张黑脉金斑蝶的图像
And I want to segment this image into a few pieces,
我想将这张图像分成几个部分
just enough to separate the background green scenery and the orange and black butterfly.
把绿色的背景和黑橙色的蝴蝶分开来
To perform K-means segmentation,
要进行 k 均值分割
I'm going to focus on one distinguishing feature,
我要重点处理一种有辨识度的特征
the color of each pixel.
即每个像素的颜色
I'll need to reshape this image so that I'm
我要重塑这张图像
feeding in a 2D array to the K-means algorithm.
使其变成一个二维数组 以便输入 k 均值算法
It should be m by three in dimension,
这样的数组维数应该是 m 乘 3
where m is the number of pixels and three is the number of color channels.
m 指像素数 3 则指颜色通道的数目
I'll also convert these values to a float type.
我还要将这些值转为浮点型
This is all done to prepare the data for K-means clustering.
这些都是为 k 均值聚类做的数据准备
OpenCvs K-means function will expect this kind of data.
因为 OpenCV 的函数 kmeans 需要这类数据
Then to perform K-means,
要应用 k 均值
I just use cv2.Kmeans function.
就用函数 cv2.kmeans
This takes in our m by three array of pixel values that we just created.
该函数需要输入的参数有我们刚创建的 m 乘 3 像素值数组、
Then a value for K which I've initially set as two.
k 值 这里初始设为 2
Then any labels we want,
还有我们想要的标签
none in this case.
但这里不需要 所以写 none
Then our stop criteria,
还有终止标准
which I'll have to define.
这也是要定义的
Then a number of attempts and finally how we
然后是迭代次数
choose our initial center points, which is randomly.
最后是初始中心点的选择方式 这里设为随机选择
But let's go back to our criteria for a moment.
我们先回来看标准
I'm actually going to define this above this function call.
我要在调用这个函数之前定义它
The criteria tells this algorithm when to stop.
标准会告诉算法何时应终止
Here, I'm making that criteria a value of epsilon or a max number of iterations.
这里我要用 ε 值或迭代最大次数来定义标准
The max number of iterations are 10 and epsilon is a value we briefly
迭代最大次数设为 10 而 ε 这个值我们曾略略提过
talked about earlier where if the clusters move less than this after some iteration,
也就是在经过几次迭代后 若簇移动的范围小于该值
the algorithm stops, it's reached convergence.
则算法终止 实现了收敛
Now I'm choosing a low value of k at
现在我先为 k 选一个较小的值
first because it will take a shorter time to process.
因为这样运算的时间比较短
And a K equal to two should produce
k 等于 2
a binary image of the two most prevalent colors in the image.
应该会以图像最普遍的两种颜色生成一个二值图像
Then K-means produces an output that results in
然后 k 均值会生成一个输出
the cluster labels 0 and 1 in this binary case and the center points.
也就是簇标签和中心点 因为这是个二值图像 所以簇标签为 0 和 1
Next, you'll want to display this result.
接下来 将结果呈现出来
To display the segments,
要显示分割情况
I'll need to convert the data back into an 8-bit image.
就需要将数据重新转成一张 8 bit 的图像
I'll also reshape this segmented data into the original shape of the image copy.
还要重塑分割好的数据 使其变回图像副本原本的形状
Now I'll be able to plot the segmented image as I would any other image.
现在我就能跟绘制其它图像一样将分割好的图像绘制出来了
It takes a short amount of time and you can see that this image
只需等一会 你就能看到这张图像
is now broken down into two distinct segments.
被分解成了两个大相径庭的部分了
One cluster is this orange value and one a sort of dark swampy green background.
一簇是橙色值 另一簇则是深墨绿色的背景
And I can actually visualize the cluster labels
实际上我可以把簇标签可视化
by displaying them one at a time like a mask.
只需将他们逐一呈现 就像用掩膜一样
Let's see the label equal to one.
来看等于 1 的标签
So here we can see that cluster one contains the colorful butterfly and flower pixels.
我们可以看到 1 簇包含了彩色蝴蝶和花朵的像素
This is our orange cluster.
这就是橙色簇
I can even go so far as using this information to mask the image at this segment.
我甚至还可以利用这些信息来对这部分图像进行掩膜处理
Here you can see I blocked out that whole segment.
你可以看到我遮住了这整个部分
But let's go back to our K-means step up here and instead of having an equal to
现在我们回到 k 均值的步骤里 在这上面 这次不让 k 等于 2 了
two let's up this K to six and run it again.
把 k 改成 6 再次运行代码
This took longer to process but now you can see six distinct colors segments.
这次运算的时间长了些 但现在你可以看到六种不同的颜色分块了
There is a brighter orange for
这是较亮的橙色 是蝴蝶的翅膀
the butterfly's wings and colors for the flowers and different green background.
还有花朵的颜色 以及不同绿色的背景
And I can do anything I want with each of these segments like masking
对于这几个部分 我可以进行任意操作 如掩膜
or performing some analysis just on the wings of the butterfly or background.
或只对蝴蝶翅膀或背景进行一些分析
So segmentation can be a powerful tool.
由此可见 分割这个工具十分强大. 最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6